Guide to the Stanford University, Pearce-Mitchell Project, Records
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Stanford University, Pearce-Mitchell Project, records
1966-1977
SC0184
Stanford University. Pearce-Mitchell Project.
1 Linear feet 1 linear foot (2 boxes)
Correspondence, clippings and other materials relating to the planning, building and inhabiting of this faculty-staff condominium project.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Provenance
Administrative transfer, Elmer Grieder, 1977-1978.
Information about Access
This collection is open for research.
Biographical/Historical note
The Pearce-Mitchell condominiums were specifically constructed The material is in English. for older faculty and staff members of the University who wished to live on campus but did not need full size homes. After approval was received from the Board of Trustees, a plan was submitted for a 100-unit apartment complex. These designs were subsequently rejected by the Land and Building Development Committee and a new set of plans for 82 condominium units was submitted and approved on June 19, 1974. Although there was strong opposition from the student body toward faculty housing on "the row" and delays due to striking construction workers, the Pearce-Mitchell Houses were ready for occupancy on September 29, 1975. The complex was officially dedicated by Dr. Paul R. Hanna on April 30, 1976.
Description of the Collection
Correspondence, clippings and other materials relating to the planning, building and inhabiting of this faculty-staff condominium project.
Arrangement note
The material is arranged by type of material (correspondence and publications).
Access Terms
Stanford University -- General subdivision--Buildings.;; Stanford University. Pearce-Mitchell Project.
Collection Contents
- Papers, 1966-1977
  - General correspondence, 1966-1977
    - 1966 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - 1968 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - 1969 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - 1970 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - 1971 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - 1972 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - 1973 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - 1974 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - 1975 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - 1976 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - 1977 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Construction items needing attention, Undated (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Faculty housing - general corresp., 1976 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Feasibility study, Undated (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Homeowners' Association - corresp., 1975 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Homeowners' Association - Bd. of Governors Minutes, Undated (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Homeowners' Association - Minutes, agenda., Undated (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - News clippings, Undated (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Recreation area, mosaic table top, Undated (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Plans, Undated (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Questionnaire - short form, Undated (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Questionnaire - second "Depth", Undated (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Questionnaire - third "Depth", Undated (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Publications
    The majority of files are undated. Exceptions are noted in the file listing.
    - Faculty & staff housing - status reports (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Photographs of dedication (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Restrictions of Pearce Mitchell Houses (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Sales materials (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Study of faculty housing, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Misc. memoranda; Grant of Leasehold (Box 2, Folder 6)